* [

    Spanish](https://citizensclimatelobby.org/es/politica-de-privacidad/)
* 

    English

    * [

        Spanish](https://citizensclimatelobby.org/es/politica-de-privacidad/)
    * 

        English

[

](https://citizensclimatelobby.org/)[](#)

* [Our Climate  
    Solutions](#)
* [Take  
    Action](#)
    * Get Started
    * Get Active
    * Take Action Now!

Privacy Policy
==============

[Citizens' Climate Lobby](https://citizensclimatelobby.org/ "Go to Citizens' Climate Lobby.") > Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy** _Your privacy is critically important to us. At Citizens’ Climate Lobby and Citizens’ Climate Education, we have a few fundamental principles, detailed below._

Citizens’ Climate Education (“CCE”) and Citizens’ Climate Lobby (“CCL”) (collectively, “Citizens’ Climate” or “CC”) operate several websites including citizensclimatelobby.org, community.citizensclimatelobby.org and donate.citizensclimateeducationcorp.org.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, CC collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. CC’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how CC’s visitors use their websites. From time to time, CC may use non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by reporting internally on trends in the usage of their websites.

CC also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments, or posting any content. CC only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below.

**Processing of Personally-Identifying Information**

Visitors to CC’s websites may choose to interact with CC in ways that require CC to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that CC gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for Community to provide a username, email address, country, city, etc. Those who engage in transactions with CC – by donating – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, CC collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with CC. CC does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

CC collects and processes an individual’s personally-identifying information only with that individual’s consent. Individuals can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information or can withdraw their previously-given consent to process such information, with the caveat that doing so may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities for which their personal information is necessary.

In addition, CC gathers personally-identifying information and tracks site usage by visitors who come to our website by clicking on a link in an email we sent. We will use this data to provide a better experience for our site users and volunteers. For instance, we can make sure that emails (and possible web content) are customized to you, so you are not asked to take actions you have already taken or that are inappropriate for you. We use this information to provide you opportunities for education and training that are best suited for your needs.

Some of the other ways CC may use your Personal Information include:

* To process your membership.
* To support recruitment inquiries.
* To provide reports based on information collected from you to local leaders.
* To keep you up to date on the latest announcements and other information.
* To provide support and assistance.
* To provide the ability to create personal profile areas and view protected content.
* To provide customer feedback and support.
* To conduct voluntary questionnaires and surveys in order to better understand our members.
* To understand more about you, so we can personalize newsletters and websites to your preferences.
* To provide information on your request to another individual such as a group leader.

**Aggregated Statistics**

CC may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites.

These statistics are used only to inform decisions on-site design and user experience; are not stored on our servers; and do not contain any personally identifiable information.  These statistics are strictly for internal use and are not published or shared with anyone outside of CC.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

CCL and CCE work closely together, including by jointly operating certain web sites. As a result, personally-identifying information collected by CCL or CCE may be shared with the other entity without further notice to you. Both CCL and CCE observe this shared privacy policy, and will honor a single opt-out if you no longer wish us to retain your personally-identifying information.

Beyond that, CC discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to its employees and contractors that need to know that information in order to process it on CC’s behalf or to provide services available at CC’s websites. The nature of the services provided by these third-party contractors includes marketing, customer relationship, and donation management, data storage, website analytics, and communication/customer contact services. Some of those employees and contractors may be located outside of your home country; by using CC’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. In particular, users in the European Union should be aware that their data will be transferred to the United States and that the European Commission has not found United States law to adequately protect the rights of data subjects.

CC also shares personally-identifying information and data about site usage with our Group Leaders, Regional Coordinators, State Coordinators, and other volunteers in leadership positions so that they can support our connection and engagement with our supporters and volunteers. Volunteer leaders are forbidden from gathering and/or using personally identifiable information for any purpose unrelated to CC’s work. For instance, we may let them know when someone in their area has completed an educational program, or when a new contact seems eager to engage and deserves a more personal connection. CC will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to any third party. Other than to its employees, volunteers, and contractors, as described above, CC discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental requests, or when CC believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of CC, third parties or the public at large.

If you participate in Washington, DC’s Host for the Climate program, the information you submit via our Google form will be added to a spreadsheet that will be available to prospective guests looking for a housing match. If you are seeking housing and enter your information into that spreadsheet, the information will also be visible to other registered Community users. Only registered Community users (as well as CC and its employees and contractors) will have access to this information. While CC intends this information to be used solely for communications about shared housing, CC does not control how other users may use your information once you have provided it to them.

In all cases, data will be stored only for as long as we continue to use the third-party contractor’s services or until you specifically request the removal or deletion of your data.

**Opt out of Communications from CC**

Email Opt-out  
If you are a registered user of a CC website and have supplied your email address, CC may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with CC. All messages sent by CC include information on how to unsubscribe quickly and easily through an automated system. In addition, if at any time you wish to opt-out of receiving communications from us, you may also send a written request to Citizens’ Climate Lobby 1330 Orange Ave #309 Coronado, CA 92118.

Text/SMS Opt-out  
You can opt-out from receiving text messages in one of two ways:

1. On your cell phone open a blank text message. In the recipient field, type 54682. In the message field, type “Stop” and then, click Send.
2. Reply “Stop” to any text message received from CCE/CCL.

Data Rights  
For requests to access, delete or correct your personal data, please contact:

Ricky Bradley  
Information Technology Director  
Citizens’ Climate Education  

**Age Restriction Compliance with COPPA**

Our services are intended for users who are 13 years of age or older. We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use personal information from children under 13. If you are under 13 years old, you are not permitted to use or access our services in any manner.

If we become aware that we have inadvertently collected personal information from a user under 13, we will immediately delete such information from our records. We encourage parents and guardians to contact us (

\*protected email\*

) if they suspect their child provided us with personal information without their consent.

By using our services, you agree to adhere to our age restrictions in compliance with [COPPA](https://www.ftc.gov/legal-library/browse/rules/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule-coppa).

**GDPR Rights**  
European Union and EEA residents [GDPR Rights](https://citizensclimatelobby.org/gdpr-rights/).

**Security**

CC takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of personally-identifying (and potentially personally-identifying) information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. CC uses cookies to help CC identify and track visitors, their usage of CC website, and their website access preferences.

See [Cookie Policy](https://citizensclimatelobby.org/cookies/) for types, data stored, purpose, and cookie expiration information.

CC visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should refuse to accept cookies when prompted by the CC sites to accept or reject cookies, with the drawback that certain features of CC’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, CC may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in CC’s sole discretion. CC encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have provided us with an email address, we will also attempt to provide you with advance notice of changes to this Policy. For non-EU residents, Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Are You Ready to Solve Climate Change?

### Get in Touch

### Jobs and Internships

### Be social

* [
    
    ](https://www.tiktok.com/@citizensclimate)

* [

    Español](https://citizensclimatelobby.org/es/politica-de-privacidad/)

©2024 Citizens' Climate Lobby. Citizens' Climate Education (CCE) is a tax-exempt 501(c)3 organization. Donations to Citizens' Climate Education are tax-deductible to the fullest extent of the law. Citizens' Climate Lobby (CCL) is a 501(c)4 organization. Donations to Citizens' Climate Lobby are not tax-deductible. 501(c)3 EIN 26-2948811 and 501(c)4 EIN 26-3521896.
